Why in America does some damn benefit
Почему в Америке какое-то блин пособие
get more than your salary, speaking
получает больше чем ты зарплату говоря
Well, you have more, in fact, I’m not talking
Ну а у вас больше по сути я ж не говорю
about us I’m saying You’re a science city, the world’s first
про нас Я говорю Вот вы наукоград первая
nuclear power plant I’m from the city of Khmelnitsky You’re
АЭС Я из города Хмельницкий Вы
from the Kaluga region, the city of Obninsk
откуда Калужская область город Обнинск
Obninsk is cool Usually simple  From Kaluga
Обнинск прикольно Обычно просто С Калуги
I came across this I will know A new city from the
попадались это буду знать Новый город с
Kaluga region
Калужской области
This is the first city
Это первый город
of a science city
наукоград
a science city where a nuclear power plant was built for the first time in the world
наукоград где впервые в мире построили
in Obninsk
атомную электростанцию в Обнинске
yes yes exactly
да да именно
about I am happy for Obninsk how the
об Я рад за Обнинск как сейчас живёт
first city in the world that built a
город первый в мире который построивший
nuclear power plant lives now
атомную электростанцию
normally calm everything is good What is the
нормально спокойно всё хорошо Сколько
population  Obninsk is
население Обнинска
now somewhere around
сейчас где-то
1.120 for example
1.120 например
1.120 I understand. How much salary do people in Obninsk receive? The
1.120 Понятно А сколько получают люди в
average in the city is probably
э средняя в городе наверное
1.70 1.70 the average in Obninsk
1.70 1.70 средняя в Обнинске
Yes now Well, let’s get some statistics, I’m
Да сейчас А ну давайте мы статистику мне
interested. It seems to me that your
интересно Мне кажется что-то у вас
expectations from salaries in Obninsk are a little too high
немножко завышенные ожидания от зарплаты
maybe that is, it turns out
Обнинске может быть то есть получается
even according to your data, this is 700 dollars,
даже по вашим данным это 700 долларов
this is the average salary America is jealous.
это средняя зарплата Америка завидует
Now we will look like
Сейчас мы посмотрим
this. I get more somewhere,
так Я получаю больше где-то
but the average is somewhere around 70.
но средняя где-то 70
That’s what they write. So Joe Filter, the average
так да пишут Вот и Джо фильтр средняя
salary in Opnetsk is 75,000 even
заработная плата в оп нецке 75.000 даже
75,000 A  it wasn’t I’m saying that it
75.000 А вот было не я говорю то что
was 65 shorter than 70 I know everything 70 Yes I believe I
было 65 короче 70 я зна всё 70 Да верю
believe 70 there is, that is, the question arises:
верю 70 есть то есть получается вопрос
if this is a science city, then there are most
то если это наукоград то есть там скорее
likely new technologies scientists And so
всего новые технологии учёные И так
on Yes, how is it that the
дальше Да как так получается что там
average salary there is 700 dollars
средняя зарплата 700 долларов
and  because we have a science city, in short,
а потому что у нас наукоград короче
here there are literally two
здесь два
state-owned enterprises that are engaged
государственные которые занимаются
specifically in
именно
science, closed enterprises
наукой закрытых предприятия
and everything else is an industrial zone. Look, I’m
и всё остальное это промзон Смотри я вот
interested, but I haven’t looked at the average
интересно да посмотрел ещё не среднюю
salary yet, but the median salary in
зарплату а медиан ную зарплату в
Obninsk, it’s 45,000, you know what
Обнинске она 45.000 знаете что такое
the median salary is? Yes, I
медианная зарплата
know, yes.  there is, for example, an average, for
Да знаю да то есть например среднее это
example, there is one who receives a million,
например есть один получает миллион так
and 10, yes, and 10 receives in hryvnia, no, I’ll
а и 10 да А 10 получает по гривне не я
just explain in hryvnia. Yes, the average
просто так объясню по гривне Да средняя
there will be 100,000. Yes, and
получится там у нас 100.000 Да Во а
the median, when we chose to sort
медианная когда мы выбрали отсортировать
everyone, so the median salary in
всех сре так вот медианная зарплата в
Obninsk is 45,000  rubles, that is, more than
Обнинске 45.000 руб то есть больше
half of the people in Obninsk receive
половины людей в Обнинске получают
less than 45,000 rubles less than 45
меньше 45000 руб меньше 45
to Well, as far as I know, as far as I know,
до Ну насколько я знаю насколько я знаю
I have one friend who
у меня есть один знакомый который
works in a small private
работает на небольшом частном
enterprise, he receives a
предприятии он получает
salary of around 50 rubles, but it
зарплату в районе 50 сся но она
varies, that is, from the bonus part
варьируется то есть от премиальной части
and so on  further, yes, maybe it
и так далее вот да может быть и
goes down and
опускается и
below I see, that is, EU copper
ниже я смот ме то есть ЕС меди
go salary statistics city of work site that is, it
го статистика зарплат город работ сайт
turns out that if the median
вот то есть получается если медианная
salary in Obninsk is 45,000 rubles 450
зарплата в Обнинске 45.000 руб 450
dollars, then it turns out to be more than half of the
долларов то получается больше половины
people Yes, half of the people, like that, half of the
людей Да половина людей вот так половина
people get less than 450  dollars, well,
людей получает меньше 450 долларов ну
look, we have one problem that is
смотрите есть у нас одна проблема такая
interethnic, let’s put it this
межнациональная скажем
way. We have a lot of immigrants,
так У нас очень много иммигрантов
in principle, this is about half the population
в принципе это где-то половина населения
that I told you, we really have
которые я вам назвал это реально у нас
problems, and the Moscow region recognizes this,
проблемы это признаёт и Московский
and so on. So,
регион и так далее Вот и
naturally,
естественно
part of this population -  These are
часть из этого населения - это
women and women who hold
женщины и женщины которая занимает
positions in certain jobs - these are
должности на определённой работе - это
cleaners, there are a
уборщицы их очень
lot of them, these women receive a salary of
много эти женщины получают зарплату
35-40 somewhere like that, but they
35-40 где-то так всё но они
are employed in one or two places, I
трудоустроены в одном в двух местах
understand that is, these are bad
понял то есть это плохая такая
statistics on wages because of migrants
статистика по зарплата из-за мигрантов
Yes  yes, yes, I understand, now it’s clear, yes,
Да да да именно понял теперь понятно да
that is, and if we discard migrants, what do
то есть а если отбросить мигрантов какая
you think the median salary in Obninsk will be,
будет по вашему медианная зарплата у
well, somewhere around 7, that is, I
обнин ну где-то в районе 7 то есть
get I, some are even more
получаю Я у некоторых даже побольше
interesting, it’s cool, well, we have
интересно прикольно ну у нас тут есть
American enterprises here and general
американские предприятия и генеральные
directors, they’re like  Well, let’s say I have an
директоры они как раз-таки вот у меня
acquaintance who works
допустим знакомый работает
at an American enterprise and
на именно американском предприятии и
let’s say when
оно допустим когда началось
it started, let’s say they came and asked, that is,
сво они допустим приехали и спросили то
the management of the enterprise. Yes, the
есть руководство предприятия Да там
workers gathered there through an interpreter
через переводчика собрались рабочие
and talked and they asked what you want, they say, some kind of
общались и они спросили что вы хотите
help, supposedly to provide Well to the
мол какую-то помощь мол оказать Ну
workers  who were mobilized when
рабочим которых мобилизовали когда
mobilization is
мобилизация
faster, so
быстрее вот
naturally, Well,
и естественно Ну у
Lord, we have a vitally important question - This is
нас Господи жизненно важные вопрос - Это
housing, yes.
жильё да
So the
Вот
general director who came is an
и генеральный директор который приехал
American, he will be and He
американец он именно будет и Он
suggested that While our guys are
предложил то что Пока ребята наши
participating in from which we implemented
участвуют в со которых мы реализовали
this is a long conversation, what is the very
это долгий разговор како самый вот
question  interesting Why do you have
вопрос интересный Почему у вас
a science city Obninsk salary
наукоград Обнинск зарплата
conversation uncle And here you are asking a question,
разговор дядь А ты вот задаёшь вопрос
look, I asked you this question from the very beginning
смотри я тебе с самого начала задал этот
and you started telling a damn story
вопрос а ты начал блин историю
Why in America some
рассказывать Почему в Америке какое-то
damn benefit gets more than your
блин пособие получает больше чем ты
salary talk Well, you have more according to I  Well
зарплату говор Ну а у вас больше по Я ж
I’m not talking about us I’m talking Here you are the
не говорю про нас Я говорю Вот вы
first science city in the world ae Why in
наукоград первая в мире аэ Да почему в
America do you get more
Америке получа больше чем вы
salary than you slow down slow down you s
зарплату тормози тормози ты с
just write on th Telegram directly at once
просто пись на й Telegram прямо зараз
axis VN
ось ВН
AK more and more respectfully YouTube taking
АК це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through srg or in yours  ban and even more
нас через срг ор в твый бан и дуже
rich video I don’t show people right now I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams for
показуе информация про стримы тому для
you, we Mali operational link to write
тоб мы Мали оперативный звязок пишиться
right behind and while there in telegrams okrim
прямо за а пок там в телеграми окрим
video shchezh tsikava and korisna information
видео ще теж цикава и корисна информация
and we are guilty of you trimati postiyny
и мы повинни з вами тримати постийний
operational link
оперативный звязок
regardless in that chi  I will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine caption
YouTube Слава Украине пидпись
with
с